<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<items>
<item>
    <title>Grand Canyon National Park</title>
    <subTitle/>
    <categoryName>National park</categoryName>
    <address>Arizona</address>
    <locatedIn/>
    <plusCode>4V4P+QR Grand Canyon Village, Arizona</plusCode>
    <website>nps.gov</website>
    <phone>(928) 638-7888</phone>
    <temporarilyClosed>false</temporarilyClosed>
    <permanentlyClosed>false</permanentlyClosed>
    <totalScore>4.8</totalScore>
    <placeId>https://34.1685153,-114.6255313,7z/data=!4m9!1m2!2m1!1sthe+grand+canyon!3m5!1s0x873312ae759b4d15:0x1f38a9bec9912029!8m2!3d36.1069258!4d-112.1129484!15sChB0aGUgZ3JhbmQgY2FueW9uWiQKEHRoZSBncmFuZCBjYW55b24iEHRoZSBncmFuZCBjYW55b26SAQ1uYXRpb25hbF9wYXJrmgEkQ2hkRFNVaE5NRzluUzBWSlEwRm5TVVJEWDA0M1NubDNSUkFC</placeId>
    <url>https://www.google.com/maps/place/Grand+Canyon+National+Park/@34.1685153,-114.6255313,7z/data=!4m13!1m6!3m5!1s0x873312ae759b4d15:0x1f38a9bec9912029!2sGrand+Canyon+National+Park!8m2!3d36.1069258!4d-112.1129484!3m5!1s0x873312ae759b4d15:0x1f38a9bec9912029!8m2!3d36.1069258!4d-112.1129484!15sChB0aGUgZ3JhbmQgY2FueW9uWiQKEHRoZSBncmFuZCBjYW55b24iEHRoZSBncmFuZCBjYW55b26SAQ1uYXRpb25hbF9wYXJrmgEkQ2hkRFNVaE5NRzluUzBWSlEwRm5TVVJEWDA0M1NubDNSUkFC?hl=en</url>
    <searchString/>
    <location>
        <lat>36.1069258</lat>
        <lng>-112.1129484</lng>
    </location>
    <scrapedAt>2021-04-15T14:22:19.898Z</scrapedAt>
    <reviewsCount>49415</reviewsCount>
    <reviewsDistribution>
        <oneStar>0</oneStar>
        <twoStar>0</twoStar>
        <threeStar>0</threeStar>
        <fourStar>0</fourStar>
        <fiveStar>0</fiveStar>
    </reviewsDistribution>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We spent one day here and had the most amazing time. The views here are simply stunning and truly overwhelm the senses. There is no place quite like the Grand Canyon.

Getting there: Drove up from flagstaff and it was a quick shot up north. Get here early as the line to the entrance builds up. We came on Easter Sunday and got there around 10:30. There was a line but it went quick.

The Park: Pretty much anywhere you go here you can find a great view of the park. I would recommend going to a visitor center as they have guides for hikes and what you can do depending on how many days you are there.

East: We drove east and there are many scenic viewpoints as well as the Tower at the end giving you some great views.

West: West has many great options and viewpoints too as well as a bus you can get on to take a scenic tour that is not open to personal vehicles.

Center: The trail of time is a truly interesting and great trail to explore and enjoy. This will give you the middle view of the canyon.

Village: Here you will find the visitors center, bathrooms, and a cafe, I would bring your own food as the food is not that great and very expensive.

All in all, you don’t want to miss this park. It is truly an amazing place.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T07:02:41.316Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>185</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We spent one day in the wonderful Grand Canyon in Arizona. We were impressed by these spectacular gorges of 1,500 m carved out over the centuries by the Colorado river.
We discovered the Grand Canyon:
- on foot, along the eastern corniche using a path with panoramic viewpoints on Grand canyon. Before hiking, we visited the Visitor centre, which has very fine displays and where the rangers are helpful.
- by plane, allowing us to have fantastic scenic overviews.  This allowed us to better understand the geology of the Grand canyon. We were amazed by all these spikes and mesas, with river Colorado in the not Tom of the gorges. The horizontal strata in the canyon recount the spectacular geological history and illustrate its four major geological eras.
- from a tower in the national park, allowing to have beautiful overview on the Grand canyon. Close to the tower, we were lucky, as we saw a beautiful squirrel!
Altogether, I highly recommend to visit Grand Canyon, with its dazzling red rocks at sunset!!! It's a magical and unforgettable landscape!!! Unfortunately, we spent one day in Grand canyon, it's not enough!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-05T17:14:46.945Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>207</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Loved it! Visited it 40 years ago as a kid and enjoyed returning with my wife on a mini vacation. Definitely plan to spend all day here if you go. Would recommend a tour company as well as they provide additional information for each stop.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T00:55:37.939Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>194</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is breathtaking. There are literally no words to describe it and you really have to see it for yourself. I went with my husband and it was insane. The workers at the park are very friendly and there are free maps given away at the gas stations. Please stay on the paths. I almost had a heart attack because a little girl fell off her bike and slightly off the path. I could not imagine what would happen if someone fell. There are no barriers to protect you. I am not one with a death wish so I did not get too close to the edge. Very very beautiful scenery and something I’ve never seen before. I will definitely be going again and doing some investigating at the bottom. Great place to go!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-06T22:36:24.262Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>32</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The chance to fly over and through the Grand Canyon was an amazing experience. The views from above were breathtaking!! I would recommend Papillon Grand Canyon Helicopters for your tour. Our pilot Mark was great. He was very knowledgeable of the area from above and kept us entertained the entire time. This was my 1st helicopter ride and 1st time visiting the Grand Canyon.  I would definitely do it all again!!!</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T13:42:32.084Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>5</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Hazy and cold, but still incredible. The shuttles weren’t running and the crowds were moderately heavy, but still spectacular. We walked six miles along the south rim. There are many great places to stop and rest or take photos.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-02T05:18:22.461Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>71</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>One of the best experiences I've ever had in my life! The landscape is what is expected of it, the place and the view are beautiful! A feeling of incredible peace and tranquility and also yields beautiful photos! We did a round trip from Vegas and it was very quiet! A few hours by car and suddenly you are there! I recommend to anyone visiting Vegas or California to visit the park !!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-19T18:46:56.676Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing amazing amazing!! It should be on the top of every bucketlist!! Don't wait until you are in your late 30s to check out this park. So much to do, so much to offer. Beautiful scenery everywhere you look!! I will be returning next year for a 4-day hike. Can't wait!!</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-17T21:25:18.075Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>319</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Friday afternoon 40 minute wait to get into the park! Warning... Stay in right lane of two lanes entering the park because it splits into 4 pay booths, whereas the left lane only has one pay booth! Right lane into park goes much faster. Don't throw your trash on the ground! Respect our National Parks-there are garbage cans near the parking lots. The Mule Deer come out in the evening all over the park for you to see &amp; run right out in front of your car if you are not careful. There is a walking trail all along the South rim with Fabulous views, bring your athletic shoes for this. Wished I had stayed two days rather than one. Also the helicopter rides are around $200 for half hour per person. Lovely place to visit!</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T02:51:54.654Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>12</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is breathtaking. There are literally no words to describe it and you really have to see it for yourself. I went with my husband and it was insane. The workers at the park are very friendly and there are free maps given away at the gas stations. Please stay on the paths. I almost had a heart attack because a little girl fell off her bike and slightly off the path. I could not imagine what would happen if someone fell. There are no barriers to protect you. I am not one with a death wish so I did not get too close to the edge. Very very beautiful scenery and something I’ve never seen before. I will definitely be going again and doing some investigating at the bottom. Great place to go!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-02T05:36:07.184Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>51</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The wildlife was EVERYWHERE! We saw elk all over our campsite, they were so gentle and kept to themselves. The place was great for a family, and very affordable. We were very pleased with the selection of grocery at the general store. We can't wait to come back!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-05T20:50:17.828Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>35</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Just today on 4/8/2021 they opened the East entrance so there were not too many people there. The park is great, but plan for full parking lots and closed facilities.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T03:59:12.078Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>43</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Great views of Grand Canyon. I’m not sure if it was because Covid or the season but a lot of the bathrooms and buildings were closed, which stinks as it was very busy. Only bad thing is parking and the line to get in.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T03:17:02.434Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>320</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wow, such an amazing place to visit. Words can't describe enough the beauty of the Grand canyon. No wonder it s one of the 7 wonders of the world. What a magnificent sceneries. If you plan to hike its better to do it early morning  or late in the evening as it gets really hot. Better to go there early spring or late fall. But if you just want to enjoy the scenery and no hiking , you can go there anytime of the year. I got my lifetime senior national park pass so  it was much easier for us to enter the park and avoided the long line to purchase the entrance  ticket on site. If you're 62 years of age and a UScitizen/permanent resident, you could get the senior lifetime pass for only $80 and it will allow you and any of your passengers in your car to enter any USA national park free. We entered the park through the south rim. Usually the north rim closes due to snow on winter. The park have a nice bus shuttle to bring you around the scenic area of the park. Bring a good camera to really capture the beauty of this place. A binocular is a plus to see all the way down the beauty of the canyon. Will surely be back again to visit this place..</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-02T01:07:35.004Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>38</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Our family was able to spend time together rebooting this natural wonder. I only wished that we had more than a couple days.</text>
        <publishAt>4 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T18:00:45.500Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>71</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Spectacular, Beautiful, Wonderful and Inspirational.  One of God's gifts to us all.
The cost per car was $35.  Nice hike around the rim.  We went during the year when it was still COLD, so be sure to check the weather as it got COLD FAST once the sun went down. Be sure to bring your camera as you will want to take plenty of photos.  Be Safe while taking your photos!</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T05:14:39.211Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>70</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>There is no other place like the Grand Canyon that brings you a strong shock of visual impact. The first of all is its immensity. The Grand Canyon stretches over 446 km and the Colorado river flows through at its valley floor. The spectacular beauty of the canyon lies its primitiveness. Each of those millions-and-billions-year-old rocks tells you its deep story. The most astounding thing in the Grand Canyon National Park is that when you are in the park, you are there, on the top of the canyon.
Walking along the rim, you could see some brave people there. You could also catch sight of little creatures like birds and squirrels. You can take the Bright Angle Trail to walk down INTO the canyon. I definitely recommend it, you just need to do what you can and to experience walking IN the canyon.
We visited the park twice. Both were in late April, which was a good choice, nice weather with comfortable temperature. The second time, we made a wise decision, staying at Grand Canyon National Park Lodges. The last photo shows you the place where we were staying. If you like camping and hiking, you should book a place in the campgrounds of the park, at the bottom of the Grand Canyon. You won’t regret it. Unfortunately I didn’t get this chance.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-12T05:53:41.461Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I went a few days ago, it was a site to see. It was amazing, great views, trails, and fun. I would keep an eye on your kids, there are very slick areas that if you fall, game over, but it was amazing. There is a lot of animals, mainly rodents, that try to communicate with a human by coming close and asking for food. Mainly squirrels, DO NOT PET THEM! I did and it was fun but there is a small risk, just pet them at your own risk, and try to resist interacting with them as of federal law and all those boring laws, and don’t if you have no food. They will bite you if you taunt them or interact with them without food, they most likely have rabies, other than that this place was a great visit and the wildlife is awesome. Mountain goat, coyotes, bighorns, deer, elk, wild horse, wild chicken, alberts squirrels, Buffalo, eagles, and hawks. Visit the Grand Canyon!</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T15:41:52.983Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome place to stay and camp especially if you can get a campground reserved. Lots of trails and bike trails to go on. Also lots of elk all over the park that are very tame around people. Watch out for ravens stealing food you have left out (and sometimes car keys too according to the park ranger).</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T17:52:22.177Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>108</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Such an incredible place. Be careful in winter as the first 1-3 miles can be snowy and icy. In late February, the first mile of each was pretty covered. Bring spikes/yak traks, and poles!

Bright angel campground is a magical place, and  Indian Garden was similar. Hiking out to Plateau point is more than worth it for the views of the Colorado River!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-15T00:05:53.360Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>100</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Doesn't matter what side your are entering the grand canyon, just know it's beautiful and prefect in any weather. When I visited it was raining all day, life for 5 straight hours and it was still enjoyable!</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T22:11:33.728Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>How some people come here and fail to appreciate the beauty of the canyon is beyond me. Beautiful and breathtaking are the first two words that come to mind.
Word of advice....wear tennis or hiking shoes. Flip-flops and heels are a very bad choice for footwear if you come here</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T18:57:44.813Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>8</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I went here 2 years ago to the north rim. I had a blast! Pictures don't do this place justice. You have to see it in person! There are no guards (that I have seen) to prevent you from falling so be careful.</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T17:59:04.818Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>32</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I loved the canyon! The rocks were nice, the air was nice, but the big problem. My pants were gone within 12-30 minutes of visiting the canyon, and I never took them off. Can someone please help I haven’t left my house in 3 weeks because no pant</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T15:21:51.852Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Nothing negative to say about our trip to the Grand Canyon! We suggest that anyone going brings lots of water, and takes their vitamins to avoid heat exhaustion! Another great tip is to use the Gypsy Guide app, as it is a great tour guide through any national park and will give you all the ins and outs of the area, with great historical facts, and all the spots to stop and enjoy the view!!</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T18:17:24.299Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome experience.  Kids loved hiking and exploring.  Mather Campground is a good site for camping.  Went the last week of March.  Laundry and showers are hit or miss so plan accordingly.</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-14T00:08:05.330Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>50</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>First time ever being here.
Don't know what I was waiting for.
Absolutely breathtaking experience.
Loved it. Employees were very nice and helpful.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-18T04:57:06.029Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>10</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The park service has upped its game with all of the improvements in the park. So clean, so many educational opportunities and different ways to see the Canyon. It was tough during Covid as the shuttle system was cut but there were then less tourists. Most people wore masks well. Warning, the fiod options are extremely limited, even harder when there are very limited ways to prepare a meal on your own if staying in one of the lodges. Limited selection and frequently out of food.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T14:23:21.333Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>97</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon is a true wonder! I have traveled all over and nothing is quite like the Grand Canyon. Hiking down to the bottom is quite the physical feat as well as just filled with absolutely stunning views</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T03:15:16.288Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>26</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Spectacular views that change every 50 feet as you hike.

A must see for everyone, but prepare beforehand. It's a unique place that's getting trashed and abused.

A little preparation and information from the Park website will enhance your trip and help you avoid the pitfalls that accompany those who aren't prepared. Don't become those special people who end up injured, dead, ticketed, towed etc.  It ruins a great experience.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T15:15:07.715Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>197</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It's famous for a reason. Maybe the most breathtaking site I've seen in my life. I visited during COVID times, but it was still worth it.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-26T02:22:30.073Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>200</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Despite Covid restrictions and silly mask rules there are huge number of people here to see something beyond imagination. Crowded rim walk at sunset. still magic ...</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T02:14:44.490Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>338</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>If you have a fear of heights like I do then this is probably not the place to visit. In my opinion, a number of people do not consider how dangerous a fall from that height would be.

The canyon itself was amazing and pictures cannot properly portray how massive it is. It certainly has the ability to make one feel very tiny while looking at this amazing piece of God's creation. While I will likely not go again, I certainly was glad that I was able to go and see it.</text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-11T18:08:53.949Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>66</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I am not sure what I can say about this wonder that hasn't been said already! It doesn't matter where you go in the park the views are absolutely amazing as you stare out at billions of years of geologic history. It truly makes you appreciate the power of nature but also the beauty as you look at just how massive this place is. This is one place you have to visit at least once.</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-14T06:39:47.963Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>229</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is as amazing as the last time I was here.  The only thing that I find is a huge disappointment is the entrance.  Each time we came into the park from town we had to wait in a line that was 30 to 60 minutes.  I'm not sure why they can not do like resteraunts do and have someone walking through the lines with credit card machines especially since they are not taking cash anyways.  Still a great time with breathtaking views that are ever changing.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-21T13:48:06.080Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>171</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful canyon landscape. It’s hard to fathom the sheer size and height of the canyon until you see it in person. Almost looks fake - like the landscape should be on another planet or in a painting rather than right in front of you. The Grand Canyon is a very interesting place that everyone should see at least once in their lifetime.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-09T20:02:29.602Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The canyon is spectacular!  Photos don't do it justice!!! This is definitely something you have to see for yourself.  It is so worth the drive.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-17T05:01:41.231Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>20</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place absolutely took my breath away!! I've been too allot of places and this is in my top number 3 of most beautiful places!! Drive to the top and you can get out and walk around and not be bothered by anyone and the view is breathtaking!! A place you should see before you die!!!!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-20T01:44:43.450Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>44</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was a beautiful place, mostly dirt and rocks. I did lose my FAVORITE pair of champion sweatpants. I saw a huge 10ft shadow, it was almost like a creature made out of pants. Anyways make sure you bring a spare change of pants, or just wear a belt!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-03T13:39:02.211Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It’s a National Park, so of course it’s amazing.
This is one of the more crowded ones, so plan to get there early if you don’t want to sit in line to get through the gate (buy a national parks annual pass ahead of time to make it even faster).
Take in the views at the overlooks, hike down into the canyon a bit (we did the Bright Angel trail, taking it down 1.5 miles to the rest house and then back up), and visit gift shops and Visitor Centers.
You can get a great feel for the area in 1/2 day, but check out the parks recommendations for things to do within the amount of time you have to spend there.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-23T03:41:08.218Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>40</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The views are about the best I've ever seen. It is a truly magical experience with lots to do, but honestly I could've sat there for 24 hours and not been bored.</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T19:38:45.902Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>12</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is the South Rim. It is open. The Cameron, Az entrance is closed. It is cold but all of the over looks are all open. This visit was in December and it is super cold. The mule trail is open and highly recommended. The hotels are open and all the gift shops. Coffee shops are open except for the visitor center. I highly recommend the "sunset at Grand Canyon"... Overall wear something warm, it's pretty cold in the winter. Stop by the gift shop and get something to take home. Enjoy a meal and have a great time. It will be a great life long experience. The views are breath taking. Thank you Grand Canyon. </text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-03T13:27:58.979Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>27</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing view and so much to see and do!
A must see to appreciate.

Safety is something that I feel needs to be added along the canyon edge as it’s very dangerous!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-04T04:41:24.750Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>29</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing 1000000x! Stunning views. Great place to hike. Not too cold not too hot at this time of the year. Not crowded due to Covid. No tour bus. No loud tourist groups. Entrance is $35 per vehicle and card only. You can drive your car the whole stretch of the canyon. Nice pave  roads. Very clean and helpful staff everywhere.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-17T04:09:38.795Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>551</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon National Park was so fun to visit! I visited in the middle of November 2020 during the pandemic. My boyfriend and I rented bicycles and biked the whole South Rim. It was fantastic. Weather was great and there were hardly that many people. What a grand and beautifully maintained park!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-04T05:28:41.744Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>90</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Very stunning and beautiful. Try to go early as foot and car traffic picks up quickly as the day goes on. Absolutely worth seeing considering how cheap it is.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T17:54:57.367Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>17</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I went a few years ago and took my pants off for a second to cool off, and when I went to put them back on, they were gone! I didn’t really think much of it until I saw all these other people with the same experience! Don’t waste your time, or at least make sure to not bring nice pants.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-02T19:30:27.622Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>When we arrived there weren't as many people as I expected, which is a good thing because it makes taking pictures much easier. With that being said, February is a perfect time to come and see the phenomenal canyon. It's cold but the perfect temperature for hiking/walking. Despite Covid-19, the gift shop and geology building are open! They have a variety of souvenirs and stuff. The Grand Canyon has very polite and friendly volunteers/employees that are always ready to help. I highly recommend visiting the canyon. I stood there for a good 10 minutes when we could first see it. It was hard to believe that it was real and not a painting! The layers are incredibly vivid and obvious. While on the trails, you can take your mask off if you aren't in a crowded area. They have trails of different levels from casual walkers to extremely difficult terrain for the experienced backpacker. I recommend waiting until your children are older if you plan on bringing them so that they can remember it in more detail and are more willing to go longer distances. Dogs are allowed on the trail but must be leashed. Stay safe and have fun!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-12T23:21:31.404Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>36</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We spent two nights here in our van. Woke up to about 4+ inches of snow and poor visibility. We walked to Mathers Point and you could not see anything. Around noon it started to clear up and the view was incredible. IT'S WORTH THE HYPE! The Grand Canyon is one of those things you have to see in your lifetime.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-06T16:29:21.577Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>38</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>All joking aside the “ big ditch” is an extraordinary breathtaking event the whole family will enjoy. A quick brisk walk up the trail will take you to the most wondrous sight in the United States. It’s hard to believe you’re only seeing about 1/10 of the 1902 square miles.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-14T02:02:32.901Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>75</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Outstanding.the covid illusion has many things closed.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-20T01:28:58.195Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>93</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Little wait to get in, about 30 minutes at Noon on a Thursday. Breath taking upon first site. Walked the South Rim for 3 miles, then walked back. Little crowded in areas around the buildings but away from them was not bad at all. Met some nice people while taking pictures. Plan to return as we only had one day to spend on this trip.</text>
        <publishAt>4 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T23:40:35.938Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>22</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Everyone should visit Grand Canyon at least once in his lifetime to see its vastness and beauty.
Start your day early as it gets very crowded around visitor centers and shuttle bus stops even at times of Covid (or late, after 2pm like we did).
Use the official national parks service website to plan your trip. They provide the recommended itinerary depending on how much time you've got. And in any case you'll need much more time than you planned.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-31T13:22:14.909Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>72</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Not much to say here. This is truly one of the most amazing places in the world. Your mind can’t comprehend the vastness of this place. Knowing that after the flood the waters that recessed back into the earth cut this epic canyon and deposited these amazing layers of earth. It’s a work of art. You need several days to truly get to know it all.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T16:22:24.881Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>176</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Majestic and beautiful. The sheer scale of it impresses me each time I see it. There are multiple ways to experience the park for many different activity levels.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T19:23:53.154Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>41</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We visited the south rim during the “pandemic”. 2 bus routes were working. Amazing views. Great food at the El Tovar. Mule ride was operational also but we had a lot of snow on the day of our tour.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T00:00:53.144Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>18</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome Park! Family loved it, breathtaking views.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T01:34:50.858Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>18</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>What can I say about The Grand Canyon that hasn't already been said? Picturesque, awe inspiring, beautiful. Went there on the Grand Canyon Railways that left from Williams, AZ.  It was a fun ride with entertaining staff.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-09T07:43:18.577Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>131</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>OH MY GOD THIS PLACE IS AMAZING AND BREATHTAKING !</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T06:16:25.100Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Big views on either rim. Both gorgeous in their own respect. There’s a lot to do down inside the canyon as well if you were feeling a bit more adventurous. An incredible park. I recommend seeing it during sunset. The rock colors sure do come out in a bit of a rainbow form. Enjoy</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T16:23:06.709Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>219</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Grand Canyon National Park One of the best experiences I've ever had in my life!  The landscape is what is expected from it, the place and the view is beautiful!  Produce incredible peace and tranquility and even more beautiful photos!  We took a round trip from Vegas and it was very quiet!  A few hours by car and suddenly you are there!  I recommend anyone visiting Vegas or California to go to the park !!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-09T09:16:29.106Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>225</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is amazing! It is so impressive it didn't even look real. It is a beautiful place worthy of a visit. Please keep it clean and pick up your trash when you do visit; This is a wonderful place that needs to be kept pristine.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-23T14:02:50.905Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>6</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is amazing! It is so impressive it didn't even look real. It is a beautiful place worthy of a visit. Please keep it clean and pick up your trash when you do visit; This is a wonderful place that needs to be kept pristine.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-23T14:02:10.342Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Iconic, historic, amazingly beautiful.  As fantastic as you thought it would be, but better.  Crowded, but they manage the crowds pretty well.  Thanks to all the rangers for their hard work keeping this place amazing!</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T02:16:12.142Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>57</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>One of the most beautiful places in the whole world and easily you can see why the Grand Canyon is one of the wonders of the world .the amazing views down the mile long journey to the bottom were so colorful and bright at the late hours of the day before darkness fell upon the canyon. I loved it and never wanted to leave. It was so clean too .no trash anywhere.i give the Grand Canyon national park my red five star rating and review and highly recommend anyone that's never been there to check it out .take your kids .they will be amazed .</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-22T23:29:09.681Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>186</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>definitely really disappointed with the all over airy atmosphere of the grand canyon. the people in the other groups were really annoying and were extremely rude to us. my friends and i got really hot and decided to take our pants off. we went on a little hike, when we returned our pants and all the other people were gone too. i am really disappointed with the staff for not acting on it i would have thought that they would take it seriously</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T15:38:18.232Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>If you show a DMV Disabled Person vehicle pass at the entrance you will receive a vehicle pass and gate code that will allow you to travel on the Red and Orange routes, normally limited to bus passengers only. Spectacular views!</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T02:04:12.454Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>43</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Had long roadtrip all the way from Phoenix, but everything paid when you reach there! Clean and fresh air yet peaceful. Weather was pretty great, was a really good time to do some hiking.
Indeed, those breathtaking views is really beautiful and magnificent! Good time to visit the park this time, less people less crowded.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-10T07:11:02.044Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>71</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A Phenomenal National Park with breath-taking views. They have an awesome junior ranger program for children, as well as some of the most beautiful scenic look-outs.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-05T05:45:04.290Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>28</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Incredible experience and hard to articulate. What a great day!</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T13:23:57.553Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>56</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon is one of the most amazing places I’ve ever been. Incredible views that change completely after walking even 15 feet up the road.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-02T23:08:20.701Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A lot of beautiful hike paths, photo op places and just awe-inspiring to see in person.  There are also bike rentals and museums that you can visit.  If you have a National Park annual pass, it works here and parking and entry is free.
Word of caution - the east side / road (the road to Cameron) was closed when when we visited but Google Maps had not updated.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T05:15:37.009Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>44</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A must. One of the best places I’ve been in the world. The trails are well-kept the stores bathrooms and grounds clean. The staff and bus drivers are very friendly. Great views from everywhere. If you go hiking make sure you dress for the right footwear and bring plenty of food and water.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-30T17:52:42.541Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>199</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>An absolute must see. We hiked down to Skeleton Point and back in 3 hours and 30 minutes of which 2 hours and 40 minutes was walking time. This is a 6 mile round trip hike. Sneakers with good traction will be okay. There's an outhouse at the 1.5 mile mark and apparently at the 3 mile mark, but we didn't see the 2nd outhouse.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-01T23:29:34.559Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>202</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I have never seen a more spectacular view in my life! You really are missing out on something truly amazing if you don't get to see it in person. Movies, videos and pictures can never do it justice.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-10T04:01:02.402Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>110</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon is breathtaking. It's almost as if your looking at something so beautiful that it couldn't be real.</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T23:10:36.213Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I mean it’s pretty friggin spectacular. I just returned from the Pakistani side of the Himalayas and I didn’t think I would see something so breathtaking so soon after returning. But the impromptu side quest to the canyon blew my mind. What an incredible spectacle. A must see if you’re anywhere close.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-09T15:30:57.355Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>210</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon - such awe inspiring majesty made from millennia of geologic mastery, this is the place, no matter where you look. You get the vastness and the unending horizon, a view of the Colorado River, rapids, and a look down into the dizzying drop below.

Ample parking during the wintery months but this park is probably heaving with bodies during the summer. Although most people seemed to stay at each lookout for about two minutes, we really took our time. It even has 5G at some points so we could video call my mom in Hawai'i to share this magnificently made miracle with her.

Absolutely cannot describe in words how majestic and miraculous this entire area is - words cannot do justice and neither can pictures. Bucket List item checked for sure!</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-28T16:57:59.779Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>180</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>2/10. I have a fear of heights, can you guys make it less deep please? Also when I tried to sit down for a second to relax (I had to because of big hike, Make shorter Please?) and I immediately lost my pants! Not only that, but it was my only pair! (Please sell pants at souvenir shop pls).</text>
        <publishAt>a day ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-13T19:32:29.676Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wow wow wow. The Grand canyon is literally a grand canyon! Beautiful view points with breathtaking driving scene along the park. You can enter the park for free with the annual pass for u.s national park which usually around $80 for the whole here. Or you can buy a one time pass for something like $40. There is a restaurant in the park and really nice gift shop. The road are safe and there is a sidewalk all over the place that you can use also for bicycles. The only downside is that after you see the first view point, it's just kinda more of the same. If you are not planning on hiking, you probably will spend here only something like 2-3 hours or less. Enjoy.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-09T23:49:58.836Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>51</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Another great place to come for vacation to appreciate all that the Grand Canyon has to offer. During summer it is extremely hot so make sure that you bring plenty of refreshments to stay hydrated.

The views are breathtaking and there are plenty of places to hike and explore. Some hikes are really high and not a lot of space to walk through. We took a hike and we were advised that if the donkeys were on their way up to make way for them by steering close to the edge where you can actually fall to, I do not like heights so I knew the donkeys would have to take that edge, sorry!

Overall, it is a beautiful place and you will enjoy brining your family and friends here.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-25T02:43:48.357Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>144</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Directions did not take me and my girlfriend to the actual grand canyon. We were led to a camping site that I paid for at the gate before realizing it was a camping ground. Would not recommend.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-03T06:11:24.627Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>5</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I don't have enough words to describe the experience, is a magical and awesome place.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T06:50:19.888Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>7</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>unspeakably majestic, every part is stunning. lots of elk, such a surreal experience. everyone should visit at least once in their lifetime.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-31T17:20:25.120Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Absolutely breathtaking. While it's impressive from the rim, there are some real hidden gems in the backcountry, away from the crowds.

If you do find yourself down in the canyon, ribbon falls is one of those places that doesn't feel like it should be real - and yet there it is - hidden away, just off the main trail.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-14T03:35:04.709Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>47</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful and breathtaking!! Amazing how the Grand Canyon was created! The park is very well kept and clean.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-26T02:43:47.054Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>10</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Flying over the Canyon in a chopper was one of the most amazing things I've ever seen. I did a chopper flight with PAPILLON then a hummer tour with BUCK WILD.  What an outstanding package.  This is a must if you visit the Grand Canyon!!</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-22T02:10:09.802Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>183</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is a must! Awe inspiring. We had  spot right next to the canyon. Wow!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-05T12:30:42.496Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>50</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Magnificent! It's a must!
One day is enough if you just looking at it from the top. But hikers and explorers will need way more time.
I went there with my folks, took some time alone, just set there, prayed did a lot of thinking, cried it out and made very important changes in my life after this trip that brought me happiness. </text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-23T07:00:01.183Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>86</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>What a place , one should not miss it if they are in USA</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-08T23:35:26.371Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>25</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Worth the visit. Stunning and humbling views with many camping spots and outlooks. Kept nice and clean like the top notch park it is.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T04:55:54.992Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>99</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It is worth every second, every penny, every point of view. A spectacle of nature, gigantic. I was in Las Vegas and I decided to do a round trip to the South Rim. If you are the only one to drive, it will be very tiring, but if you have 2 or more drivers it is much more relaxed</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-19T19:18:22.297Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Definitely a must-do trip!! We did a day tour from Las Vegas, which was a bit long (14-hours) so we were exhausted by the end of the day. It was absolutely worth it, the views are incredible and the park is really well maintained. I would love to do a helicopter tour next time, but walking up and down the canyon was an incredible experience. Definitely recommended!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-10T20:06:47.424Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>31</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The most magical place in the U.S.  Below the rim and on the river is a trek worth making.  You cannot believe the views the canyon offers below the rim.  I will go back as often as possible.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-01T03:19:34.327Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>57</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Bring water!!! Lots of it in the summer. Best hike for elevation gains.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-04T08:03:48.283Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>154</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It is heart-winning to watch this. Its every shade and every stone seems unique in itself. The arrival of sunlight, then climbing and the redness of the evening light gives a savory feeling. In this calm atmosphere, the noise of the river water keeps connecting us  with ourself. The greenery found in these red stones seems to be unique. In the daytime, the soil has become like ours friend, showing clouds in the open sky becomes a screenplay. After a full day's journey, sleeping under stars at night gives a feeling of paradise. This travel offers an exciting and enjoyable experience. Sometimes it seems like we have come to another world.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-12T14:30:00.541Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>198</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wow. What an exciting  and exhilarating area. Spectacular views of this canyon can be seen in Mathers point.   These breathtaking views shown were at sunset.  Amazing.   I am sure I will came again at a deferent time to see what it looks like.  These were taken in December.   Park and take the walk.  It’s worth it.   Awe inspiring.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-03T03:18:40.793Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>183</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Finally FINALLY got to visit this beautiful piece of mother earth! Been a dream of mine since I was little and grew up watching "Paulie" and "Fools rush in" ! Moved into my van Spring of 2019 and finally traveled to Grand Canyon Summer 2020! Spent the night and woke up there just like I always dreamed of doing! Best experience I couldve ever ever imagined ever and thanks to Covid hardly anyone was there so i felt like it was a wonderful private viewing party with just me and my dog Cujo! Hope your time is as magical as mine was </text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-24T23:05:07.366Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>33</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>My husband and I visited in the middle of March. It was very cold and snowy. Even though we were cold, we still enjoyed ourselves. The views were amazing. We didn't stay long due to the fact that it was very cold and we didn't have a 4 season camper. We would've liked to have done more, but we headed south to Tombstone after 2 nights in the national forest.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T13:54:21.305Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>19</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We had a great visit to the park. Entry fee is $35 per car with special rates for military. The east entrance was closed which backed up the south entrance for at least 45 minutes. Once we got through the gates it was a straight drive in to any look out points. It was also very windy and cold. Recommend hiking boots and water</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-25T23:23:24.599Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>43</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The sheer scale of the Grand Canyon is breathtaking, and the natural beauty and grandeur will be forged into your memory forever.  just incredible and beauty all around and incredible wildlife in the park</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-04T06:09:28.057Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>213</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>You can't get better views. It's amazing. Summer is hot and crowded... But, it's worth it. Winter is less crowded, you can drive out to hermits rest in your own car.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-15T05:24:10.185Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>53</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Very beautiful! Commercialized a bit, and as of March 2021, need to wear a mask in most areas near the visitor center.</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T13:04:06.492Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>70</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The only bad thing I can say about the Grand Canyon is that is also welcomes a grand amount of tourist at any given time. There are crowds almost everywhere, which makes it difficult to truly appreciate how magnificent this place is. Other than that, it's simply the Earth's masterpiece. We spent 12 hours there, walking, eating, hiking, experiencing both the sunrise and the sunset. We saw dozens of different animals and some interesting plants, too. I wish we had time to hike down the canyon to see the river. Maybe next time.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-08T23:31:19.174Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>329</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>For your visit:

Coming in the summer? Beware, there will be massive crowds and despite the ample parking area, it will all be packed, so be prepared to drive around for a while and then walk to the rim. The South Rim offers great views, but if you're there during the summer, I would suggest going down the Bright Angel Trail and seeing it all first-hand. The views are amazing and unlike anything you can see if you stay on the rim. It's also good to visit in the winter if you dislike crowds.

Also, if you're there for the summer, be sure to check out the North Rim. It's closed during the winter and a bit of a drive, but it's worth it. The Kaibab Trail is amazing and has much fewer people.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-27T23:52:15.439Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>303</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The iconic natural American landmark holds up to all the talk which surrounds its beauty. I traveled here in September of 2018 for Labor Day, flew into Phoenix, rented a Jeep, and drove the next day up to the Grand Canyon Park. I was there with a friend who flew in from San Fransisco to meet me at PHX. I loved every park of this canyon although to be honest once we arrived at the park I said to myself "where is the canyon" "is this a scam" apparently you are required to walk from the parking lot area to the entrance of the canyon, which I did not realize. Once we made this hike and reached the canyon we had a few minuets until the clouds opened up and rain began to fall.</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-01T06:25:54.059Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>124</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Guano Point is my fave on the west side. Must see. Give yourself time to take it all in. Be prepared for whatever kind of weather it may bring. If you eat outside, you will dodge the ravens. But definitely check out Guano Point, it surrounds you with a spectacular view on both sides. Bring a friend! Enjoy!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-24T07:01:46.191Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>59</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Breathtaking, spectacular, beautiful. Worth the trip to experience nature at it's best. Bring tons of water as it can get very hot.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-08T19:46:49.955Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>39</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The canyon is interesting, definitely a lot of rocks and dirt. Unfortunately somehow myself and many of the people in my campsite lost their pants. I have no idea how this happened as i never took them off, we had to make do with putting shirts around our legs. Great trip but i definitely would like the pants problem to be resolved.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-31T15:15:30.467Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The place we stayed was fantastic. Yavapai Lodge. Grand Canyon was special. God truly blessed us with this miracle. It's a gift. It's a must that each American should truly have this place on their check list. To walk/touch this place is a blessing it's an honor. To think once, our Americans Indians were the true owners of this grandeur. It's so spiritual, it's hard to believe it's on earth.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T03:31:07.352Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>58</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>There isn't enough words in the English language to adequately describe the grandeur of this place!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-11T14:07:14.267Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1582</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Great scenery trip! The pilot was a great tour guide and we learned so much along the way</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-23T04:22:30.186Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>166</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>First visited here in 1991 and the following year. So it was 28 years since I last visited and I was just as awe struck as the first 2 visits. We did a 4 day backpacking trip to Horseshoe Messa on the South Rim and loved it. I will be back again and it won't be 28 years!</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-12T14:54:19.164Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>47</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon National Park welcomes all who prefer an unspoiled environment for introspective thought and intrigue. I could not take enough photographs of one rock or canyon to satisfy the changing light and should have camped outdoors instead of a suite.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-29T01:28:44.905Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>205</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was great to see the Grand canyon again and it was even more great to see so many people walking around WITHOUT masks on, bucking the US government's communist trends.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T05:26:41.442Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>54</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>3</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Breathtaking scenery  to be seen no where else.  Lodging on rim available.   Shuttle available. Wild animals.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-12T22:52:55.457Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>230</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Who says I don't like the grand canyon? During the summer time it may be extremely crowded at the south rim. If you go in the off season you won't find the crowds and you will not find the heat. With a little bit of snow on the ground it made for a very comfortable experience</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-18T18:12:14.674Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>70</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is a great place, but I have two main concerns; firstly, I feel as though there are far too many rocks here for my liking. Perhaps consider taking some of the rocks and moving them? Secondly, I had to buy new pants after my visit, as all of my pants as well as my family’s mysteriously disappeared. This may be an issue. Thanks.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-27T05:17:28.975Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Grand canyon hiking is great right now.   It is not too hot,  no insects,  no snakes and fewer people.   We hiked down into the canyon and there was packed snow on the trail for the first mile or two. Shoe traction crampons are helpful,  but not necessary. There were a couple of inches of snow on the south rim.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-01T01:28:40.116Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is certainly for most folks a bucket list item. Dis not fail to live up to the reputation it so tightly deserves. Had a great stay near the park in a dispersed camping area called Long Jim - very very close to the south park gates.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-16T01:05:38.955Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>86</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>You would think the name would sum it up, but there aren't enough descriptive words to describe it and there isn't a photo that does it justice. When you first see it, the magnitude of the distance is unfathomable because there is nothing to compare it to. I went New Year's Eve and it was 26 degrees, cloudy, and snowing. Being from Alaska, this made the scene relatable and even more awe-inspiring. Removing it from my bucket list is almost saddening because it signifies a time to move on, and you will never want to move on from the Grand Canyon</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-11T19:21:33.403Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>125</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I could rate the Grand Canyon more than 5 stars. We had a plane from Bolder Airport to the West Rim of the canyon and then a helicopter ride to the floor of the canyon and then a raft ride on the Colorado River. What an experience.  The other time we visited the South Rim and stayed in a motel. Both visits were different but both stunning.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-03T19:07:41.732Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>198</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A landmark everyone must see once in their lifetime .

We came here during the Pandamic and felt very safe during our time here.</text>
        <publishAt>4 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T16:35:23.399Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>32</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Simply incredible! Of course, the amazing views make the experience - I've never seen anything like. The cars and crowds were a bit nuts, but there was plenty of parking and shuttles. The South Rim trail was extremely nice, offering multiple excellent views, and with plenty of amenities along the way. A truly great experience here!</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-06T23:59:38.187Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>298</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>In the winter, you get to drive the rim.  Buy the America The Beautiful card for all of the parks.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-28T06:18:25.384Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>43</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>very nice place, but when i decided it was enough and and wanted to walk back, this weird old dude ran up and stole my pants. watch out for those, either way, still 5/5 would reccomend it</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T21:44:25.257Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>11</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We hiked down Bright Angel trail, camped at Bright Angel Campground, and hiked up South Kaibab the next day. It was EXHAUSTING- to say the least- but completely worth it. If you're physically fit and up for camping I'd absolutely recommend it! Gorgeous views and the river is incredible.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T14:19:48.253Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>23</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>December 2019 was a game changer for my Physical Fitness world. I pushed to hike the southern rim of the Grand Canyon to the Colorado River and back in a single day totalling 45K plus steps. On the way, witnessed magnificent sunrise and came across cool but challenging terrian. Try the hike... you will love it.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-15T00:40:32.730Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>15</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Feeling of ever expanding vastness takes you millions of years back in time.
Make sure to check if shuttle service is operational to avoid walking back the whole trail that could lead to extra time.
Bring binoculars.
Water bottles and some food.
Drones not allowed.
Merchandize available at visitor center.
Taking $80 annual pass is worth it if doing other national parks.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-25T05:49:39.688Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>117</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It really is a natural wonder of the world.   I came with my teenage daughters and we walked the Kaibab trail down to cedar ridge.   It's winter holidays and crowds are surprisingly low.

Be prepared for the hike up.   Switchbacks can get brutal if you aren't ready.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-01T08:22:16.828Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>49</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Pictures do not do justice when it comes to the grand canyon. This place is Incredible!!!</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T16:20:00.348Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>44</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I recommend going really early and catching the sunrise because there's not many people there and you have prime viewing spots.</text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-11T15:46:20.428Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>23</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Woah....
Amazing views, astonished by this place.
Definitely a lot of people, but hiking down into the canyon is definitely worth it.</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T15:05:37.782Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>If you have not visited the Grand Canyon you’re missing out a very beautiful place. I know a big hole in the ground doesn’t sound that amazing but it is a sight to only fully understand by seeing with your own eyes. If you’re the hiking type its absolutely fantastic. You can also take the train from Williams AZ (which offers a fun Polar Express train ride during Christmas), and even stay at historic lodges/hotels inside the park.
- I highly recommend getting the National Parks Pass if you plan to visit more than one National Park in a year
- Don’t go in the summer... late fall and early spring are perfect, but so is winter when the snow is on the caps
- Get ice cream by the hotel
- Take your time... and bring food with you cause you’re gonna get ripped off at Grand Canyon Village which is just before the entry to the park

Enjoy! The views are amazing!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-05T07:01:08.152Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>71</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>BEAUTIFUL ! Passed thru arizona made a quick stop and it was just amazing to see , the only thing i saw that was just sad is due to covid they require masks and the masks are turning into trash all over the ground.we seen at least 7 in the hr and a half we were there. Either get rid of the mask mandate or be cleaner ....</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-25T16:59:11.365Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A must see once in a lifetime place. Unless you're hiking or some other activities, a couple days is plenty to see all the sites along the south rim.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T15:54:02.143Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>69</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Incredible!  A testament to what a treasure our national park service is!  Wish we had more than three days to hike and explore, but so glad to have done it. FYI the main visitor center is still closed, but busses are running, bathrooms are open and there is park lodging.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-23T01:43:48.087Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>117</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I read all these reviews about stolen pants... so I went with underwear only, me, my wife, my two kids and grandma. Smart family! Until we all fall asleep and we woke up with pants on! My favorite banana underwear is gone...</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T15:24:08.046Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was very nice to see the Grand Canyon for the first time and so nice to see so many people NOT wearing masks. Fight the Communists.</text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T04:01:52.590Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>7</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Grand Canyon lives up to its hype - every sight is memorable and every photo you take is worth to be printed in a magazine. Absolutely gorgeous and breathtaking scenery. I’ve been to many national parks in the US and Grand Canyon is my #2 so far (after Yellowstone). Tons of trails to hike and each side of the canyon provides a unique experience. Make sure to bring enough water and warm clothes as it can get cold and windy. Parking can be a pain but they open up additional lots farther down the road (if you’re coming from the South side). Also make sure the check out Horseshoe Bend and Lake Powell nearby.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-22T15:07:12.542Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1069</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>My job shut down 2 weeks for Xmas so I jumped to it and drove 1800 miles from Ohio to see the Grand Canyon. Even in the winter its beautiful. If you come and it's foggy don't lose hope because the weather changes by the minute! I watched the fog move over the peaks and it just lifted revealing the canyon. You can also walk along the rim to the Hopi House where they sell gifts.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-30T00:15:58.695Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>44</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Marvellous and mesmerizing!

It, indeed, is a wonder of the world. This was my third visit to this national park and it never ceases to amaze. If you are in AZ, it is a must go place.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-20T21:23:45.630Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>20</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wow!! This was a perfect place to start our honeymoon! We stayed at Yavapai Lodge inside the park, which allowed us to get out and explore a lot of the South Rim.

We made sure to get up every morning nice and early so we could catch the sunrise. It is an experience that words cannot describe. The canyon is a wonder, an absolute wonder. We caught ourselves just gazing at the scenery and not saying a word.

We are really looking forward to coming back and doing more, like some of the hikes down in the canyon. You could easily spend two weeks here. Make sure you have good walking shoes, and the ability to take pictures, lots of pictures!!</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-02T21:18:13.972Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>50</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>First time at the Grand Canyon. We took the train out of Williams and it was so fun. We ate at the El Tovar Hotel.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-27T00:19:35.737Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>74</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Visit at golden hour and you won't regret it! It will be a little cold, but if you're just going to the Ooh-Ahh point, you'll have plenty of time to go down and up before it gets dark! Truly breathtaking.

Note: Visited prior to Covid, so things may be a little different.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-18T20:09:31.474Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>266</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Located in Arizona, Grand Canyon National Park encompasses 277 miles (446 km) of the Colorado River and adjacent uplands. The park is home to much of the immense Grand Canyon; a mile (1.6 km) deep, and up to 18 miles (29 km) wide. Layered bands of colorful rock reveal millions of years of geologic history. Grand Canyon is unmatched in the incomparable vistas it offers visitors</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-25T08:37:49.211Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>145</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Simply stunning! We were lucky enough to arrive a day after it snowed (Dec. 29, 2020) so the view was amazing! Make sure to arrive early because it does get packed and the line to get into the park can get really long. We arrived to Mather Point before 7:30 am and there was less than 20 people already there which was perfect to get some gorgeous shots of the Grand Canyon.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-17T20:27:38.427Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>14</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I visited the Grand Canyon in 2001 and consider it to be one of the highligths of my life. It is truelly awesome. Seeing it on TV is a joke. You need to stand there on the edge of the canyon looking down. Then you realize the immensity of this miracle of nature.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-10T14:41:54.213Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>391</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It’s the Grand flipping Canyon!  The park is clean and there is so much to see and do that one cannot simply take it all in in one visit.  There are many places to eat, camp, hike, learn and have fun.  The Grand Canyon should be seen by every American at least once in their lifetime.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-07T13:31:29.143Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>393</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The canyon itself was beautiful and the paths were great, however the bathrooms were so disgusting I wouldn’t even trust putting 3 layers of toilet paper down to sit down.</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T23:44:37.873Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>2</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful sight. Impressive as it can be, pure nature and simply amazing. A lot to do in one day, take you time and enjoy</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-16T07:13:49.293Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>222</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Took me over 3 hours just to get to the gate.  And surprise, surprise, no parking.  I do not have a handicap sticker, but need a cane when doing a lot of walking.  Finally found a place to park and was able to make it to see the canyon.  People were rude, adults bumping into me with no apology. Kids totally unconscious of their surroundings and people.  People with their dogs on a long leash, is quite the trailer.  I was actually glad to get out of there!  If you go be sure to stay in the right lane as much as you can.  It goes much faster.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T08:31:43.219Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>124</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>3</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It’s a place like out of this planet, is like you’re looking at it and you can’t believe its real. This place its magic, manifest, astonishing , admirable.. photos don’t describe not even 1% of the real thing </text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-02T15:53:28.667Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Out of this world. Crazy people though jumping from rock to rock. I can see why there are deaths.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T12:43:20.228Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>12</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Massive yet peaceful formations of earth reset the perspective of life. A wonderful experience worth taking!</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-07T02:16:31.240Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>94</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>One of the 7 natural wonders of the world. What more can I say, or need to fir that matter.</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T23:32:07.140Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>64</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Pictures are an understatement. This is an overwhelming beautiful park. Everyone must see this marvelous wonder. I stopped off for a Sunset view. There are walking paths that lead you around the park. Parking is $35.00. Don't worry if you don't have a ticket. You can purchase one as you enter the park. [Check for gate hours]. South Rim is open 24 hrs. COVID-19 Compliant. The Visitor center closes at 3pm, but the park is open 24 hrs. There is a Grand Canyon Nature Conservancy Store that provides a view of the south rim for viewing and some cool quality gift shopping. There are restrooms and plenty of parking. Check weather. It was pretty cold and windy when I arrived. Bring water.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-10T18:02:39.009Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>82</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>My husband and I have ventured here twice. During our last journey my husband was able to make it all the way to Phantom Ranch at the bottom (Bright Angel Trail). I made it to Indian Garden (half way) and decided to turn around. We both had a great time a some personal revelations, not to mention we did it all in 12 hours or so.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-31T20:16:51.547Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>34</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Breathtaking views and indescribable moments!! Definitely a must see in Arizona!</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-18T20:15:23.483Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>32</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Food at phantom ranch was excellent. Get the steak!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-06T11:48:20.425Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>15</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful scenery, not crowded and peaceful place. Must visit this place to get close to the mother nature. Went there early morning to see sunrise. Breath taking views. Time will be always short.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-19T09:23:17.716Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>22</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was limited due to COVID and the winter weather but it was not crowded at all! We loved every minute of it. I highly recommend getting there now while the crowds are down. Just dress warm!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-25T03:02:03.657Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>35</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Eye catching - meet original natives of America - red indians @grand canyon. Must visit</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T17:44:27.533Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>28</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was just amazing to witness such astonishing landmark. Will be returning soon to be able to head down Bright Angel Trail.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-22T05:10:21.667Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>23</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Obviously, absolutely amazing! We learned a few things for our next trip. The right lane of the highway leading up to the park moves much more quickly. It’s best to arrive before 10am.  Probably before 9am.

We hiked the south rim trail. It was great. Our teen boys could explore in certain areas away from the trail and closer to the rim (scary for mom). Next time we come, we will plan to hike down into the canyon. Do your research before you come. I didn’t do such a good job of this. But we had a good visit, nonetheless. Also, we learned that we will bring our own lunch next time. Spent $60 for sandwiches and chips. The shuttles weren’t really running at full operation, so my husband and son had to hustle back to the car to come pick us all up once we got real tired. Wish those shuttles would have been running.

Overall, terrific time. Would love to, and hope to, return.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T18:03:28.504Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>it's a fantastic n breath taking view of the deepest formation rocks from the top @ every angle</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T13:38:27.334Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>13</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was beautiful. It’s famous for a reason </text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-13T08:40:43.134Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>20</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Absolutely breathtaking! Highly recommend visiting here. It's an easy walk around, and you get to see quite a bit of the Canyon. There are also serval small shops that are fun to visit.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-09T14:26:45.729Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>76</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I've always loved this park. Personally it has been a great honor and unexpected blessing, that to my fortune from a very young age, bestowed upon myself did to my father's profession. I've been here many times, to and experienced many different adventures related to the Grand canyon... OMG.

All I can say is, there is no words that can express the feeling, and out the experience of this majestic national treasure, one of seven wonders of the world in person. You just have to see for yourself, or you will never understand the majesty, and awesome auxillirating spiritual experience... Yourself in person the only way you'll comprehend that unique experience...</text>
        <publishAt>4 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-11T08:06:52.044Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>107</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Absolutely a once in a life time type experience. The vastness is unfathomable. Your mind can't comprehend all you see. Such a blessing from God.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-17T01:33:34.932Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>80</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The majestic beauty and splendor is so spectacular, no photograph could ever truly do it justice. It is an awe-inspiring, breathtaking site to behold.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-13T19:42:32.228Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>69</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Loved it here. Saw as a kid. Much better as an adult. Great views and vibes.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-22T03:30:43.591Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>558</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Of course one of the most beautiful places in the world.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-06T23:29:41.523Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>296</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I love this park. One of my favorite National parks.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-10T00:25:29.765Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>321</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>One of most magical places in US!

This park is a great gem in the list of National treasures of America! Every corner of park has take my breath away.

So many spots, trails, overlooks! Be sure to check ahead with a park rangers which roads are closed and before entering check updates on their official website! Due to the Covid-19 there have been made many changes.

Bathrooms are opened.

We visited on a Christmas Day, 2020 and only one - South entrance was opened.

Park has some points where you can drive your own vehicle and some where you can get by park shuttle bus.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-26T22:51:08.750Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>166</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>You can't really say anything bad about the grand canyon, always a little crowded, but SO worth it. With covid the visitor center is closed, on the south rim at least, but they left advice and ideas of what to do which was nice:)</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-31T18:36:25.545Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>36</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Absolutely breathtaking!
Make sure to be there at least once in your life!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-13T19:50:23.998Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>774</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Very busy, but gorgeous. Very dog friendly which is nice when you travel with pets.</text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T12:33:54.413Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>19</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>There are no words to describe the breathtaking scenery that awaits when you visit the Grand Canyon. It is everything that people say and more. We were lucky enough to visit after some early season snow and it was the cherry on top of the ice cream.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-14T02:36:25.403Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>74</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Loved it the view was so breath taking beautiful</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-25T04:09:10.177Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>53</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing!!! I was only there for a couple of hours and i regret not staying longer! They are currently taking payment ONLY online due to covid and the visitor center is closed but i managed to take some pictures of the recommendations they had outside.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-22T09:20:25.377Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>32</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is amazing! I don't even know how to describe it beauty. My wife and i stayed here for 2 nights and wish we could have stayed longer. We hiked about 2 miles down in the canyon to a nice spot and I could have sat there for hours just staring. Everyone one needs to go to the Grand Canyon at least once in there life.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-16T01:45:46.531Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>75</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Very beautiful for what we could see. We went on a day in March and it was snowing. Visibility was horrible but the bus route drivers were great and friendly!</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T16:39:57.879Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>143</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing place. The views are just jaw dropping,especially when the sunrise or sunsets hit. ❤</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-22T02:11:58.087Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome place. Order your pass online for faster service passing through the main checkpoint. Make sure you drive to the Desert View Watch Tower on Road 64 from the South Rim Visitor Center</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-01T15:19:10.024Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>54</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>No words. Breathtaking is the closest!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-08T02:22:02.562Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>124</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Made a one day trip out of this on our way to see family in Scottsdale. The line to get in is long during the daytime, so expect a 45-50min wait in line. Once in the park, the shuttles are running on limited capacity due to COVID. Do yourself/family a favor and skip the shuttle if you're simply wanting great views of the canyon and hike along the rim towards and then past Mather Point. Our inexperienced hikers of ages 14, 11 and 6 made the two-mile trek to the trailhead and then another 1 mile trek down into the canyon to Ooh Ahh point with no issues. The mile trek back out definitely gets your heart rate up, but nothing too taxing. Another two-mile trek back to the visitor center for a full-day of sightseeing. Bring snacks and plenty of water.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T21:13:31.441Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>61</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was closed but still a cool drive.  Edit* The north end was closed but south and west are open</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T19:06:44.083Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>173</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It really do be beautiful. The expanse of this canyon and unobstructed views of the striated red and tan earth seem to be as far as your eyes can see. The roads were good and the trails on the rim and throughout the park was clean. The spring water is amazing and many locations to stay hydrated. Definitely a wonder of nature.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-19T03:03:51.327Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>17</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful park with enough activities to keep us busy for a few days. We took the advice of many reviewers and decided to stay overnight at Bright Angel Lodge, well worth it!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-29T00:30:42.099Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>864</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Such an amazing place to see. Everyone should go once in their life!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-24T21:11:53.222Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>70 million years old, and you are a speck when you stand next to it  I’ve never seen a picture that really captures its breathtaking presence and beauty. It’s definitely a GRAND Canyon. Somehow the things that seem so huge in life right now grow smaller when you are near it.    Just a little glimpse I think of how things look from God’s POV.

Favorite lodging- the Xanterra line: El Tovar, Bright Angel, Thunderbird. Book a year in advance to stay in Billy’s cabin.</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-07T14:40:49.602Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>55</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome. Heed my words,”Stay in Williams, get to the park by 8:30 am and keep right at entrance “. Your welcome!! Lol</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-31T23:19:22.331Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>As you can imagine, breathtaking. I was passing through in the fall and didn’t know if I would get to see it but after meeting some friends in Joshua tree and getting invited to join in on a mule ride along the southern rim I couldn’t say no! And so happy I didn’t, I fell in love with my mule, Ella, and learned that the geology of the Grand Canyon has an acronym: D.U.D.E. Deposits, uplift, down cut, erosion! Zack was our tour guide and if you’re interested you can even go on an overnight trip down to phantom ranch in the canyon. We did lose electricity in the park for most of the day afterwards but Alexa and Russell had sandwiches and we spent more time admiring one of the greatest wonders of the world. It’s wild to think about just surviving in the elements when you’re surrounded by a desert and a gigantic gorge. But Zack also taught us how useful the land really is and how the indigenous people thrived in these areas. Pretty incredible to think about in our modern world.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-30T23:07:26.202Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>31</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wow! Breath taking! Bucket list item checked off! There isn’t much to say other than you Must Visit here at all costs! It’s an amazing experience. Easy to get to, just make sure you have some time to drive, it takes about 1.5 hours to get to the national park from i40. West some comfy clothes and good walking shoes. Food is a bit overpriced but what do you expect. Overall amazing</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-24T05:41:09.793Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>40</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Pants gone, not my good ones but a decent pair. I fortunately caught some malnourished and balding man trying to sneak them while I was taking a nap I, beat him good for trying me a second time. This is a picture of my lovely jeans, not my favorite ones but a good pair.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-01T19:55:24.410Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>12</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>2</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>So breathtaking. Even though we went when it was colder, we enjoyed our time. No pictures can ever compare!</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T11:08:22.209Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>17</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The grandiosity of Grand Canyon could not be described in words. It's one of the 7 natural wonders of the world, says it all</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T03:39:09.576Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>136</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Words don't do it justice! Absolutely breathtaking.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-05T03:21:58.895Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Majestic...no no no i take that back.. there aren't any words or photos that can do it justice.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-12T01:30:40.800Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Excellent hiking trails with magnificent views if you hike down 2 miles. Must do.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-03T06:45:22.022Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>16</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Definitely a MUST SEE!
This is one of the best places you can visit in the world, and there are countless reasons why it is on everyone's bucket list. Its landscapes are incredible, especially during the sunset and sunrise. Pictures and words just don't make it justice! You can explore the area on foot or riding a mule; don't forget to bring lots of water and sturdy shoes.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-19T21:49:50.067Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>478</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>A must visit place if you're nearby, but one thing to consider is thru traffic via the East Entrace as it is closed due to Covid.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T05:39:50.359Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Kids got a thrill Mom &amp; Dad got pictures. The family had a bonding moment</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-06T19:44:26.567Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>20</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazing place, one more item checked on the bucket list </text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-11T19:17:01.517Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was a very fun trip except when me and my husband went up to get a closer view, we were knocked down on the ground. When we stood up our pants were gone. Please fix this in the next patch, Thanks.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-17T10:09:25.587Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Absolutely beautiful. Please don't go to the very edge to make pictures! My friends went early summer this year and a lady was there with her family making pictures, walking backward and fell off. When I was there a couple with their young daughter were right on the edge, not even watching their daughter. So dangerous!</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-22T19:39:35.473Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>62</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Few places will ever live up to expectations, Grand Canyon is a exception.
No words describe the gift nature has given here. Well worth 35$ to make sure future generations have the chance to enjoy it exactly as generations before us got to.

Free offroad camping just outside the park entrance. Very friendly to van or car camping (free clean toilets, water, and trash/recycle, in the park)
Go as early as you can.
Get to the gate before sunrise, you can pay on a machine at the gate, and have the park to yourself before the crowds wake up.
Park service maintained the roads well in the snow.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-15T04:18:41.288Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>19</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>My name is Roger Browning and I am a writer. I wanted to tell you my experience of the Grand Canyon when we were able to visit it in precovid times. Here I go. We arrived the south entrance after a quick stop at the Flintstone village for my daughter to run out her energy and play. We made our way to for our camping and took time to set up our tent. A bull elk, intimidating and strong, walked his peaceful way through the camp between our newly set tent and the offered fire pit. He didn't seem to even notice we were there, but knowing them as I do, we watched, but made every attempt to stay clear. There were mule deer that followed and the camp seemed lively with the birds. We didn't even notice other campers from the sights and sounds that kept us so unaware. We made our ways to the restrooms and showers to spruce a little for our trek, so clean more than to be expected, roughing it we would not be. We grabbed our packs and staff to make a short canyon trail walk, then made our ways toward the overlook to sense what was ahead. My lord! So beautiful our bounty of the glorious natural wonder before us. The deep fall of the surface brought in all of the shadows, reflection of it all. We stood that first overlook long enough, that it delayed our walk start down. We toured its rim there taking in more and the next day would be our start. Grand is just not the sole word one could use to describe such a magnificent place. We took in the flight of the Condor's as they made their ways back to their roost. A wonder almost prehistoric in view as their wide wings gave the appearance to scale, that of a hang glider as they appeared before our rail. I am the age of the Brady's and it was for that reason we were there, as I remember the bunch on their weekly show and a vacation that I wished to be with them there. Don't live your life without seeking this out, so magnificent and devine the experience. I cannot wait until post pandemic to make another trip there, just like the twenty since that one before. My name is Roger Browning and my book is about inhertance gone wrong. A story of a troubled family of dysfunction and greed with it's setting that of a modern day ranch. Please enjoy the canyon and I hope you enjoy my book. Look me up. You can find it on amazon and for your search it's known as 'The Reckoning of Rance.'</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-26T23:25:43.899Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>169</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I recently took my family on a trip from Las Vegas, Nevada to Grand Canyon National Park. We brought my two daughters, my wife, and my dear old mother with us. We made a quick roadtrip from Las Vegas to Grand Canyon National Park. They loved this experience. I shocked them by taking the trip in the middle of the summer, but they loved every second of it. I can't wait to come back and explore again. We will be back.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-09T23:06:06.075Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1039</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The best place I visited till now in USA. We went to the Kaibab trail. Our total trek took 10 hours (down and up). We didn't go all the way down as it was getting darker and we had to go up. We went up till a spot where we could see the Colorado river clearly. The trek terrain is rocky/gravel/sandy. Please carry water and energy drink for your trek. There are toilets on the way down however you'll need to trek a lot to reach these facilities. I only saw one drinking water facility however it said that water needs to be treated before drinking. This trek is not for everyone.  Trekking upwards was challenging at some points and please take some short rest before proceeding ahead. The weather was cold- sunny -cold. Altogether it was a worthy trip and will come again next time to reach the base of the Colorado river which I couldn't finish this time.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-31T02:50:24.343Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>nice canyon but in the end only some rocks laying around. was kinda chilly</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T14:27:21.096Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>8</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Rode the Grand Canyon Train to the Park on our first day.  Beautiful day but we didn’t get to see as much as we wanted, so returned a 2nd day, via car, saw Angel Trail from the Rim Trail (red bus) and then walked some of the Rim Trail. It’s all so breathtaking.  One day is definitely not enough to take it in.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-18T20:41:37.902Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>5</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I thought it would be a good trip, I took my seven kids and my husband and when we got there it was quite nice. But when we were going back, we realized that we had no pants! All nine of us were stranded, pantsless. Please fix this problem soon!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-27T05:08:32.602Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>it’s the Grand Canyon. it’s amazing. breathtaking</text>
        <publishAt>6 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-08T22:05:10.162Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Few can name a protective snail that isn't a loving chimpanzee? A reflective blueberry without tigers is truly a eagle of punctual pears. Some posit the affable alligator to be less than fair-minded; Ducks are perfect prunes! The literature would have us believe that a patient peach is not but a plum?</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-28T22:26:43.637Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>5</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Hiked the Bright Angel trail, was an amazing, only the 1.5 mile and back up, and gotten caught in a thunder storm coming back up, was scary n cold about 50. Made it back up, took our time n kept moving. Definitely a great trail, but be prepared and take your time!</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-23T02:52:48.713Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>61</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Try to do a hike into the Canyon on one of the trails. Without that your visit is incomplete.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-03T02:18:11.884Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>98</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Not sure why it's a world wonder. It's great, but not superior to other places that are not called "wonders." A bit too touristy.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-01T04:01:07.933Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>38</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Really nice place!!! You can't loose the view during sunrise and sunset, it is just spectacular. You'll need to be ready to walk a lot, even when there are shuttle buses that helps you to move from site to site.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-25T02:47:38.733Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>49</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon is one of God's beautiful creations. The Grand Canyon is "Breathtaking". I go above highly recommending exploring the beauty of the Grand Canyon!!!!</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-06T13:20:09.397Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>104</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I know this says Grand Canyon National Park in general but this is the North rim and that is a whole other experience. You'll have to find the adorable little Jacob Lake village, it has an inn, camping, and a general store. Turn south after finding Jacob Lake and you'll find one of the most picturesque drives. Deer and bison can be found on the way to the North rim, keep an eye out for the table rocks they're worth stopping and climbing on. Have fun and enjoy the wild.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-29T20:22:31.281Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>45</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Just breathtaking. Get away from the visitor center a bit and it gets even better. Almost a shame to hike when you can just stare at the beauty. I recommend the highest point hike. That forest is recently burned it's a whole different experience. Bit apocalyptic</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-07T08:17:54.649Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>65</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Its so beautiful  worth the drive to go see it</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T15:59:45.744Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>151</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was great! Everything was great about it the view the breeze and the smell. But I have a major problem with this place. I was with my wife and two kids and we were hiking and stopped to take a break. We accidentally fell asleep and when we all woke up our pants were gone without a trace. When we were going to our car to get a pair of pants we were stared down and laughed at. We are all scarred for life because of it. My kids now have to go to school and everyone there knows that they lost their pants and are now being bullied because of it. 1 star!</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T15:54:48.057Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This place is amazing. I am from Scottsdale, AZ myself. We went up to Flagstaff for the weekend. So we went to the Grand Canyon Railway, which is a train station that takes you up to the canyon. The train ride is about an hour and a half. When you get their they drop you off and you walk to the canyon. When we got there, we were so amazed. It is so big in person it’s just amazing. There are some cool shops and restaurants. Obviously if you have a free weekend you should come up here. This place is AMAZING. BUT DO NOT FORGET BE CAREFUL OR YOU MIGHT FALL OFF.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-18T22:48:20.697Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>65</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>What can I say? It was grand. Beautiful and plenty of hiking and walking trails for any person.</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-13T02:03:21.419Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>24</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Entering the park was a challenge took 40 mins for
2 miles, cost is $35 per car. But it was worth it, visited Grand Canyon after 20 years so many improvements, new lodge at the park. Forrest Ranger are very friendly and helpful.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-28T14:57:58.618Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>21</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>it was so pretty! And the food was lovely :)</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-21T01:03:46.274Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>6</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful park, a true natural wonder and the pride of Arizona.</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-10T02:18:49.234Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>37</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I visited the North rim this fall and have been to the south rim maybe 20 years ago. I preferred the South Rim in the winter. There were some great fall colors at the North Rim and the area near the visitors center was pretty busy but the rest of the park was pretty light. It all starts to blend together after a few viewpoints.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-12T16:31:52.806Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1039</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Waited on the road for 1.5 hours to see the beauty. After reading on the website everything was OPEN, got there to the opposite.....CLOSED.CLOSED.CLOSED!
The canyon was BEAUTIFUL!</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-15T21:45:23.674Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>2</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Incredibly!!! Breath Taking!! Worth the drive!! Everyone should visit The Grand Canyon at least once in their life. Best Road Trip ever!! Visitor Center is always clean and full of friendly staff. If hiking the Grand Canyon is your thing I recommend planning at least a few months is advance. Food &amp; snacks are offered for purchase. Plenty of shuttles to take you to all the different lookouts. Good Walking shoes are a absolutely must!!! No Slip on shoes or Flip Flop sandals. Sunscreen!!!</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-18T19:25:35.396Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>76</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Canyon is beautiful, but wait times to get in are very long</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-04T22:56:11.363Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>166</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>the canyon was very large and i didn’t like how it was so big, it was advertised smaller. i also lost all clothing there. i was skeptical because i read the reviews about losing your pants, and i was very careful. instead, i lost everything. very embarrassing to ask a park guide for help when you’re completely naked. please fix this.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-16T09:16:42.915Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>One of the best places I’ve ever been. Great to do it in a private helicopter with champagne</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-08T03:29:24.901Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>241</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Just one of those things you have to see. Absolutely amazing.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-17T04:27:10.394Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>43</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It's the grand canyon, what else can I say.</text>
        <publishAt>3 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T01:03:58.843Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>324</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>1st time here. OMG! Pictures can not possibly do this place justice! The sheer size is SO MUCH  bigger than I ever imagined. Unfortunately, I was only able to see it in the daylight for about 1 1/2 at sunset. Can't wait to go back and see it at sunrise. Lots of cabins to camp at along with campsites.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-13T05:44:51.803Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>135</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was nice lots of things to see and to do I got to see wild horses and elk bulls .</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-02T19:53:29.356Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>40</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I went to the Grand Canyon a few years ago. I had to go by myself which was a drag. But I still had a blast and enjoyed my time there immensely.
I want to take my wife there soon. It is truly one of the most beautiful sights you'll ever see. Along with Niagra Falls.
This is a great National Park. A must see.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-29T19:30:46.651Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>134</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It’s really even more breathtaking than the pictures</text>
        <publishAt>2 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-12T19:45:58.096Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>31</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Stopped at the lodge and had amazing pizza their beers and drinks were also great. The views are incredible nothing else like it. Not extremely busy so our experience was really nice. Definitely worth the drive .</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-21T00:35:33.432Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>11</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Beautiful and breath taking.. you can hike a couple miles down. Or you can hop out on the extended rock shelf's. Gorgeous View any way you look.</text>
        <publishAt>9 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-07-07T04:37:26.055Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1134</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Great fun for a family stunning views</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-10T03:35:43.739Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>24</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon was AMAZING!!! Trails were clearly marked and the visitor center and gift shop were great</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-14T17:45:35.708Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>26</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>It was the best time at Grand Canyon National Park</text>
        <publishAt>5 days ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-09T15:44:38.949Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The East entrance was closed because of pandemic. If you plan to go from the South entrance to the east to reach the Horseshoe Bend, please check if the East entrance is open. However the view is amazing.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-04T18:58:35.719Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>3</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The West is the best. If you’re going to visit the canyon, I encourage you to visit the west side. Worth the money and views!!!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-18T03:56:38.459Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>155</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Great hiking and running adventures here! Did my first R2R2R on October 27, 2020.
Life time experience await you here!</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-19T03:12:47.750Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>100</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Northern rim is the best. Stay in the park if possible. Southern rim is more crowed so we prefer the north.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-12T16:22:09.847Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>30</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is the first national park I visited during spring break from my University day's. and the first time I ever went out camping in USA. Amazing experience. Very well organized and maintained national park. There is a store nearby to get camping equipments if you missed any. #ಅಲೆಮಾರಿ-ಜಂಗಮ</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-08-23T17:43:17.137Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>136</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Visited the South rim in the last couple of weeks. We stayed inside the park which we now regret. If you are going I recommend you stay somewhere outside of the park and the reason for this is everywhere we went the staff at every business were rude and inconsiderate. The staff at the deli and store were just down right rude, they acted like it was an inconvenience to serve us. Do they forget we are their customer? The large lady at the fudge/book store was absolutely the worse. She was rude and abusive to my grandson which is only 9 years old. She needs to be fired and should not work in any customer service related job ever! Besides the horrible customer services received, the places you stay inside the park are old and dirty. Probably never go back, but if I do I will look outside of the park to spend my money. The people who work in the park are very rude and need to find other jobs.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-04T15:45:47.448Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>2</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Finally cross this off my bucket list.  The views of the canyon was breath taking.  I am glad I finally made it.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-20T06:13:08.364Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>27</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I visited the Grand Canyon during one of its busiest seasons. The road leading to the South Rim was congested with traffic and vista points where crowded with tourists. I opted to take an aerial tour of the area which took about 45 minutes. The helicopter ride was amazing. It gives you an opportunity to capture magestic scenery from the lens of a camera.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-18T18:16:58.554Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>180</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>"As water reflects the face, so one's life reflects the heart" always find time to enjoy a soul nurturing moments and share it with wonderful  people ❤ beautiful sunrise  another beautiful fall season... can't wait to see this place on winter.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-25T17:35:38.612Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>397</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Well it’s not called the Grand Canyon for nothing. We got the bus from Tusayan to the south rim and nothing quite prepares you for that first view over a massive gaping canyon stretching ten miles over to the north rim and dropping 5,000ft to the Colorado river, a silver strip winding its along the valley floor. Magnificent, awe inspiring, insert your own adjective here but if you get the chance, visit this marvellous natural wonder. We walked along the south rim trail for a few miles taking it all in before watching the sun set at Hopi point.</text>
        <publishAt>a week ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-04-07T15:33:50.191Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>98</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Cool experience, we came when it was like 115 though and holy cow. Definitely come in the cooler months.</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-11T23:50:40.350Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>119</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Love this park, so many beautiful views, hikes, and plenty of places for foods and souvenirs ❤❤❤</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-22T22:46:51.032Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>38</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Way to deep. i want there with my entire direct family (about 600 people) and we ALL left without pants! we didn’t even notice they were gone until we had all driven home! please someone fix this problem.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-26T12:01:58.630Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Sometimes you need to see something bigger than you to give you perspective. Everytime I see the GC I remember how small we really are and to spend valuable time with people we love most!

If you've never been, it's a must see ✨</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-08T00:09:51.064Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>14</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Flew to Vegas. Took a road trip to see this amazing site. Bucket list kind of things.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-03T00:49:31.264Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>94</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Awesome! Some trails were a bit icy, but well worth the struggle!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-22T23:41:43.617Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I was there during covid and they take all the proper precautions. It's a great place to just be able to do what you want. I would HIGHLY recommend putting it on your bucket list. You can not beet the veiw. Its breathtaking !!</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-13T06:26:36.965Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>26</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Second time visiting, and the feeling of smallness never disappears. Such a jaw dropping beauty that awakens the imagination and captures the mind. Entrance fee is done via QR code on the welcome brochure due to covid. And masks were optional throughout, some with some without. Worth every minute spent reaching this natural wonder!</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-30T17:09:18.135Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>100</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Being here is the reason why we call America, the beautiful. This is a place you must visit once in your life and take it all in. This is what a postcard view looks like. Highly recommend it but check weather and bring sweater and warm sweats pants because it can get chilly.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-01T13:03:04.039Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>23</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Simply stunning!

Everywhere you looked it was like a beautiful painting. The scenery, the colors.

The view constantly changed depending on your viewpoint, the location you were on the rim, the time of day, etc.

Sunset brought a whole new set of photos for you to take. This time of day lit up the canyon with stunning rays coming out of the clouds.

Wildlife is abundant. On the south side we were able to see birds, squirrels, a vole (see photo) hiding underneath a rock, elk, wild horses, etc.

It was humbling to know that this beauty was created out of the world destruction of the flood. To also know that this was all created in a matter of months is mind boggling.

This place puts our (humans) place in the universe into perspective. We are so small compared to everything else.

Definitely worth visiting and staying for more than a day.</text>
        <publishAt>10 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-06-09T01:14:48.654Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>35</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon is more majestic than you’d ever think (at least for me it was that way). The day I visited it was a hazy day, due to the numerous fires around the area, but still brought about a unique view many may not see when they visit here.
My visit took place during COVID, so there was a limited amount of people along the popular South Rim. If you want an experience with less people, at the expense of a little bit more difficult route to get to then go to the North Rim. Any of the views you visit here however will be worth the visit.</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-19T08:59:32.845Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>45</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Words cannot possibly describe the absolute wonder. If you have a chance to see the Grand Canyon, take it!!</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-01T18:02:11.489Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>20</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>We know that the kind duck reveals itself as a relieved bee to those who look. The dynamic lobster reveals itself as a decisive raspberry to those who look. A fish is a warm grapes. A chimpanzee is the snail of a dog. A modern currant without hippopotamus is truly a melon of ambitious fishes. The literature would have us believe that a sincere prune is not but a kiwi! A lemon of the dog is assumed to be a charming scorpion? Waking to the buzz of the alarm clock, coherent camels show us how squirrels can be cherries. If this was somewhat unclear, some posit the thoughtful prune to be less than perfect. Some posit the witty lemon to be less than eager.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-16T12:51:19.144Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>17</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Stop #2 has the best sunset view. Don’t miss out!</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-13T06:58:14.007Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>8</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Not really my sort of thing so guess.... It’s a really big Canyon.. If your into Canyons this is for you. I’m more of a beach guy.........</text>
        <publishAt>a month ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-24T23:30:31.287Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The kids loved it. The views were amazing. I was scared my reckless child would run off the edge but he did not so all is well.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-19T01:34:36.324Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>6</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Have to see it in person to understand.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-28T03:06:51.818Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>93</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Amazin place .the angel trial is hard I was my first time in that kind of walk but I don't regret, I do it again</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-19T18:26:57.784Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>52</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I live in Grand Canyon National Park, don't get me wrong, It's lovely. but I keep seeing tourist all over the place! As a ten foot creature made out of pants, I adore stealing their pants, but I have to say, these little tourist are getting on my nerves, and they need to bring more pairs of pants. I've also heard they are planning to exterminate me which I take offense to. Please take care of this tourist glitch, I am just a ten foot pants creature who wants to live in peace.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-19T01:56:19.157Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>1</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is really cool place to visit. Really beautiful</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-29T19:49:07.286Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>38</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I absolutely recommend it!
You must visit the Grand Canyon if you go to Vegas or somewhere not far from the National Park. It is interesting to have a guide who explains you about it, or a helicopter to see the views from above. No matter what you do there you are going to enjoy it a lot for sure!!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-13T20:41:30.609Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>240</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>I was stunning!! If you really want to explore you need more than one day. Bit one day will get you some amazing views and an easy walk</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-02T15:38:52.327Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>17</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>An adventurous lemon's cat comes with it the thought that the exuberant blueberry is a prune. It's very tricky, if not impossible, a kitten sees a horse as a discreet rabbit. A protective lobster is a cat of the mind. Nowhere is it disputed that some gentle crocodiles are thought of simply as monkeys? One cannot separate hippopotamus from discreet crocodiles.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-16T12:51:16.600Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>15</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This was my first time visiting. There's no way to experience it all in one day, and pictures do not truly capture what your eyes are beholding. I suggest doing research before you go. Weather and covid caused some closures while we were there, but it was still amazing!</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-24T22:59:53.255Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>26</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Nice place to visit. Love it.</text>
        <publishAt>4 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-16T05:30:44.655Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>33</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Very cool place. Be aware of closures of north rim entrances and highway, I would call before making drives to different areas of the park lest you waste 2 hours in the car if you’re not going to the main park entrance (like I did!). Definitely go at sundown, the colors of the sky and Canyon are like out of a painting. Also get up and see the sunrise!  The hike to the canyon floors takes a two day trek one down, then one up and when I was there in November the trail was iced over so you had to had crampons and ice gear lest you literally slide off the mountain face. Instead so the rim hike and take the bus to Hopi point or past it and walk back to the El Tovar lodge.</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-11-22T18:47:55.680Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>18</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The beauty of the grand canyon is out of this world. Being next to the edge of the high altitude cliffs may be scary but it was definitely worth checking out.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-29T23:39:46.291Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>4</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Honestly this tis the most underwhelming if the two national parks in Arizona. Don't get me wrong, the view is breathe taking and the scenery is fantastic, however unless you are doing a hike it gets very stale very fast. The visitor center is fantastic, the national park merch is high quality, and over a lot of fun. The best part of both times I've been to the park is when I saw a moose use a crosswalk to cross a street. Overall 10/10 would watch cross the street again.</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-18T19:28:49.801Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>40</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>4</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>The Grand Canyon was designated a World Heritage Site by UNESCO in 1979. The park celebrated its 100th anniversary on February 26, 2019. The Grand Canyon, including its extensive system of tributary canyons, is valued for its combination of size, depth, and exposed layers of colorful rocks dating back to Precambrian times. The canyon itself was created by the incision of the Colorado River and its tributaries after the Colorado Plateau was uplifted, causing the Colorado River system to develop along its present path. The primary public areas of the park are the South and North Rims, and adjacent areas of the canyon itself. The rest of the park is extremely rugged and remote, although many places are accessible by pack trail and backcountry roads. The South Rim is more accessible than the North Rim, and accounts for 90% of park visitation. The park headquarters are at Grand Canyon Village, not far from the south entrance to the park, near one of the most popular viewpoints. Grand Canyon Village is the primary visitor services area in the park. It is a full-service community, including lodging, fuel, food, souvenirs, a hospital, churches, and access to trails and guided walks and talks.</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-08-20T03:31:52.604Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>726</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Bae thought he was in Mars, I had to remind him that we drove there and we didn’t take a spaceship there, oh bae. The sunset breathtaking.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-24T01:31:58.901Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>14</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>"Nothing prepares you for the Grand Canyon. No matter how many times you read about it or see it pictured, it still takes your breath away. Your mind, unable to deal with anything on this scale, just shuts down and for many long moments you are a human vacuum, without speech or breath, but just a deep, inexpressible awe that anything on this earth could be so vast, so beautiful, so silent.Even children are stilled by it. I was a particularly talkative and obnoxious child, but it stopped me cold. I can remember rounding a corner and standing there agog while a mouthful of half-formed jabber just rolled backwards down my throat, forever unuttered. I was seven years old and I'm told it was only the second occasion in all that time that I had stopped talking, apart from short breaks for sleeping and television. …
… The scale of the Grand Canyon is almost beyond comprehension. It is ten miles across, a mile deep, 180 miles long. You could set the Empire State Building down in it and still be thousands of feet above it. Indeed you could set the whole of Manhattan down inside it and you would still be so high above it that buses would be like ants and people would be invisible, and not a sound would reach your. The thing that gets you - that gets everyone - is the silence. The Grand Canyon just swallows sound. The sense of space and emptiness is overwhelming. Nothing happens out there. Down below you on the canyon floor, far, far away, is the thing that carved it: the Colorado River. It is 300 feet wide, but from the canyon's lip it looks thin and insignificant. It looks like an old shoelace. Everything is dwarfed by this mighty hole."
The Lost Continent
by Bill Bryson</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-24T15:41:27.371Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>463</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Glad we finally got here! More beautiful than I expected. Drive out to Lapin point for sunset... You won't be disappointed!! Pictures don't do it justice...</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-13T06:01:05.147Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>105</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>So amazing we hiked down to the bottom and stayed the night so Worth it 100% must see</text>
        <publishAt>3 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-22T23:46:12.574Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>9</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Took the forest service back dirt roads into the Grand Canyon area. There are miles of long dirt gravel roads that allows for horseback riding camping and all-terrain vehicles, before the main Northern entrance that charges just to enter.  Check with the ranger station if you're going to the Grand canyon and you don't like crowds and/or need an inexpensive place to camp. They are a bit rough on your vehicle and tires though however if you have animals it's worth it. My dog enjoyed the thoroughly enjoyed the trip and for the most part I was able to keep her off of a leash.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-01-30T18:23:19.189Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>13</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>No picture can ever describe the depth and beauty of this enormous wonder of the world.</text>
        <publishAt>2 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-02-08T00:25:34.132Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>29</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Wonderful trails, lots of parking, and well maintained park. The only downside is the looong line to pay. You get to the front and they just hand you a map with a code to pay during your walk. The website is useless and the internet connection is non-existent. I'm guessing there's a lot of folks taking advantage of how hard it is to pay. It is a place that you have to visit at least once in your life, one day is not enough to know this wonderful place</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-26T11:51:03.666Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>15</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>This is such a great place to visit, you must have it to your bucket list!</text>
        <publishAt>3 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-28T16:46:59.267Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>11</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Too high up and too steep. Why did they dig the canyon so deep? Not a kid friendly place, Mason fell off the edge of a cliff and a search team has been looking for him for 3 days. Arizona sucks in general too.</text>
        <publishAt>2 weeks ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2021-03-26T16:59:32.128Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>5</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>1</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Really well maintained national park. We did the Bright Angel Trail to the Indian Garden Ranger Station hike and it was absolutely beautiful. The 4.5 mile climb back up to the Bright Angel trailhead was tough, but really felt great to say we did it! Really worth the trip and I can't wait to come back and hike to the canyon floor!</text>
        <publishAt>5 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-31T23:07:00.283Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>34</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Despite having been here a few times before, this past time was the first in which we had our camera to take pictures. The canyon sits around 4 hours driving from Phoenix to the south rim. This is where a vast majority will visit since it’s more accessible than the north rim which is just an out and back road. If you do decide to visit the north rim it is only about 1.5 hours more of a drive and will allow you to go by Horseshoe Bend along the way. We have always gone in via the entrance to the east which has given us views from Grandview Point and The Watchtower. Both of these provide good views but we recommend going to Navajo Point to see more of the Colorado River without having to hike further out. It is the highest elevation point on the southern rim which gives you a better view down into the canyon. It does have a small parking lot which can be tricky during busier times of the year. We initially didn’t plan to stop by on this trip but since it is so close to the areas we were in we decided to for a bit. Because of this we did not try to hike down and weren’t able to get the types of pictures we wanted. When we do go back we hope to hike down and be able to see the canyon during the sunset or sunrise. Because of the color of the rocks and the lack of shadows it can be hard to photograph the canyon and truly capture how it is. Nevertheless, it’s worth a visit and can be crossed off your list in an easy one day trip!
- @wanderingwithustwo</text>
        <publishAt>9 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-06-16T23:03:19.038Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>125</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Ummm its one of the World Wonders! Beyond that it is a well laid out, reasonably priced, easily accessible national park. I entered the South Rim entrance and spent my time along the South Rim trails and activities. There is something for everyone, at every comfort outdoors level. Wheelchair access to trails and the rim are above and beyond. Can be crowded to get the 'best views' but really is there a bad view here?</text>
        <publishAt>7 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-09-03T15:03:45.228Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>176</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>true</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Excellent!!! We took the Grand Canyon Railroad train in a round trip to the Canyon  and had a wonderful trip. We walked around, went to the Hopi House and the had a dessert snack at the El Tovar hotel that was built in 1903-1905. It is an amazing piece of history (108yrs old).</text>
        <publishAt>4 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-12-09T01:34:17.519Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>31</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
    <reviews>
        <name/>
        <text>Breathtaking lots of room to be by yourself. Easy parking. Easy trails. Every lookout is breathtaking look out for Elk on the way in and out. They are big and they were very vocal. Great Day For Sure.</text>
        <publishAt>6 months ago</publishAt>
        <publishedAtDate>2020-10-04T02:20:08.660Z</publishedAtDate>
        <likesCount/>
        <reviewId/>
        <reviewUrl/>
        <reviewerId/>
        <reviewerUrl/>
        <reviewerNumberOfReviews>36</reviewerNumberOfReviews>
        <isLocalGuide>false</isLocalGuide>
        <stars>5</stars>
        <rating/>
        <responseFromOwnerDate/>
        <responseFromOwnerText/>
    </reviews>
</item>
</items>